Finding Aid for the Ruth Frey Axe Collection of Material about H.H. Bancroft and Company LSC.1427
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Bancroft hard-cover imprints
  - Bancroft Law
    - Letter HRW Montana Historical Society, May 16, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      - Reply: May 24, 1949, Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letters HRW Nevada State Library, May 16, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      March 3, 1964 to Mrs. Hater
      March 6, 1964 Nevada State Library
    - Notes Oregon Supreme Court Reports, Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter Oregon State Library, June 2, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter Robert Greenwood, March 4, 1964; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter to Robert Greenwood, March 1, 1964; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter to Utah State Historical Society, March 3, 1964; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      - Reply: March 6, 1964, Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter from N. Orwin Rush Director University of Wyoming Library, December 7, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      re Supreme Court Reports.
    - Letter of Ellen Crowley State Librarian to HRW, May 24, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of Mrs. Hager to State Library, March 5, 1964; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of Dr. Andrew Horn, November 11, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      4 pages, lists of UCLA, Bancroft.
      - HRW reply, November 16, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Note, Item No. 86; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - 2 letters - HRW to Los Angeles Bar Association, October 25, 1948 November l, 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter Thomas H. Dabagh, November 5 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      re Am. State Reports and Am. Decisions
    - Letter Howard Jay Graham, January 18, 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Librarian of Congress, November 8, 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      - Reply Francis X. Dwyer Acting Law Librarian, Library of Congress, January 11, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Homer Crotty, (Gibson, Dunn & Crutcher), August 7, 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      - Reply: Mr. Crotty, August 4, 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of Mr. Crotty, July 30, 1948; Item No. 86; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Mr. Dabagh, November 23, 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Mr. Howard Jay Graham, January 16, 1951; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of Mr. Dabagh, November 15, 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Librarian Hastings College of Law, January 13, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of Mr. Dabagh, December 8, 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Librarian Yale Law Library, January 4, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW with copy to Librarian Yale Law Library, December 23, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW go Mr. Dabagh, December 14, 1948; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of Cecil Skipwith, May 18, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of Ruth Axe to Francis R. Doyle, Reference Librarian, Boalt Hall, September 18, 197[?]; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
      - Reply, September 15, 1972; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Page from Bancroftiana regarding find of Labatt., (May, 1857); Item No. 86; 3 p. Xerox copy of Labatt (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Howard Jay Graham, January 23, 1951; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Notes, Item No. 86; 4 pages, on yellow paper (Box 4)
    - California Supreme Court Reports Reporter's Edition, Item No. 86; 6 pages (legal size yellow graph paper) (Box 4)
      "very important for Bancroft Law Imprints List"
    - "My notes", Item No. 86; 5 pages. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence Bancroft Whitney
    - Letter from A.A. Herschley to HRW, November 19, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter from C.E. Brumm Library Services Counsellor, September 8, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter from HRW to W.K. Kuhl, September 20, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter from Kuhl to HRW, September 15, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter from HRW to Mr. Brumm, September 11, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Mr. Herschler, September 21, 1949; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter from to Mr. Kuhl, October 25, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter of Mr. Kuhl to HRW, October 30, 1950; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter from Poster to Mrs. Hager, August 19, 1965; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter to Mr. and Mrs. Hager from Mr. Taft, June 17, 1965; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter to Mrs. Axe from Mr. Taft, June 17, 1965; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter from Mr. Taft to Mrs. Hager, July 17, 1965; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter to Mrs. Axe from Hager to Mrs. Axe and Mr. Taft, July 8, 1965; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Letter from Mrs. Hager to Mr. Taft, August 4, 1965; Item No. 86 (Box 4)
    - Check List of Sumner Whitney law publications, Item No. 86; 12 pages, newsprint (Box 4)
    - Notes, Item No. 86; 1 page, newsprint (Box 4)
  - UCLA and UC, Item No. 87 (Box 4)
    - List of Bancroft imprints holdings, Item No. 87; 6 Legal size pages (Box 4)
      Checked by both institutions with additional information.
    - List Bancroft A.L. Imprints checked by UCLA, Item No. 87; 6 pages (newsprint) (Box 4)
    - List checked by UC Ed and UCLA List of H.H. Bancroft imprints, Item No. 87; 9 pages (newsprint) (Box 4)
    - List with UCLA library nos., December 4, 1949; Item No. 87; 4 pages (Box 4)
      - Covering letter dated December 13, blue paper from Andrew Horn to HRW, Item No. 87 (Box 4)
    - Lyman List, Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter and list of Andrew Horn to HRW, July 23, 1951; Item No. 87; 3 pages (Box 4)
    - Letter and list of Andrew Horn to HRW, December 1, 1949; Item No. 87; 3 pages (Box 4)
    - HRW to Andrew Horn, February 2, 1949; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Andrew Horn to HRW, February 14, 1949; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - (RFA list) H.H. Bancroft & Co. publications, UCLA, Item No. 87; 9 pages (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Mr. Andrew Horn, March 30, 1950; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Andrew Horn to HRW, September 28, 1948; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Andrew Horn, March 14, 1950; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Andrew Horn, August 18, 1951; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Andrew Horn to HRW from Washington D.C., July 10, 1951; Item No. 87; 3 pages, holograph (Box 4)
    - HRW to Andrew Horn, June 2, 1951; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Wilbur Smith, August 30, 1951; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Wilbur Smith to HRW, August 17, 1951; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Wilbur Smith to HRW, August 23, 1951; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Dr. Ed. Carpenter to HRW, August 11, 1950; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Ed. Carpenter (Lyman library), August 11, 1950; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Dr. Carpenter to HRW re Savage Manual, October 5, 1949; Item No. 87; 1 page. (Box 4)
    - HRW to Ed Carpenter re Savage Manual, September 30, 1949; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Ed Carpenter, August 26, 1949; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Ed Carpenter to HRW, August 25, 1959; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Wilbur Smith to HRW, January 28, 1956; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Wilbur Smith, February 4, 1956; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Notes, Item No. 87; 1 page, yellow paper (Box 4)
    - Wilbur Smith to Ruth Axe, July 15, 1959; Item No. 87; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HH Bancroft bibliography, UCLA prepared for H.R. Wagner, September 28, 1948; Item No. 87; 4 pages (Box 4)
  - Directories, Item No. 88 (Box 4)
    - Chart of Bancroft firms, Item No. 88; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Chart of Bancroft firms, Item No. 88; 1 page, both marked 4 (Box 4)
    - Chart of Bancroft firms, Item No. 88; 1 page, also marked 4 (Box 4)
    - Notes, Item No. 88; 1 yellow page (Box 4)
    - Charts of Bancroft companies, Item No. 88; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - [?], Item No. 88; 1 yellow page, marked 4 (Box 4)
    - Bancroft firms as listed in directories, Item No. 88; 3 orange pages (Box 4)
    - San Francisco Journal of Commerce, August 12, 1886; Item No. 88; 1 page (Box 4)
    - San Diego Union, September 26, 1886; Item No. 88; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - A.L. Bancroft and Co. addresses, 1885 to 1896; Item No. 88; 2x5 card (Box 4)
    - Letter from HRW to Gladys Wickson (California Historical Society), November 21, 1949; Item No. 88 (Box 4)
    - Bancroft Family and companies, Item No. 88; 12 pages, Legal size (Box 4)
    - Newspaper articles re The Fire of April 30, 1886, Item No. 88; 7 pages (Box 4)
    - Miss Wickson to HRW, May 24, 1948; Item No. 88; 1 page (Box 4)
      - HRW to Miss Wickson, May 29, 1948; Item No. 88; 1 page (Box 4)
    - S.F. Directories, Has Brouck, Item No. 88; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter of Miss Wickson re Directories Colley and Schmidt, January 16, 1950; Item No. 88; 1 page (Box 4)
    - San Francisco Directories: Nathan J.and F.Stone, Item No. 88; 3 pages, yellow (Box 4)
    - HRW to Wickson, asking for info re W.H. Knight, July 19, 1948; Item No. 88; 3 pages (Box 4)
    - Business addresses S.F. Directories W.H. Knights, Item No. 88; 2 pages. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence with bookdealers and with Hagers, Item No. 89 (Box 4)
    re my Ban. checklist and their Zamorano-Ban. Index and Swingle, [?], Dawson 2, Dawson cat. with Ban. items.
  - Folder marked Bancroft correspondence, Muybridge, [Paper manufacturing], Item No. 90
    [not included BB 1/84]
    - Letter from Cordon Hendricks requesting information re Muybridge, Item No. 90; 4 pages, notes
    - Letter to Warren Howell re pub. CheckList, May 26, 1973; Item No. 90
      - Letter from Warren declining., Item No. 90
    - 2 Letters from Burt Cahonn requesting info. re W.E. Bancroft, Item No. 90
    - Letter from James D. Hart re early Ban. imprints, September 15, 1972; Item No. 90
    - Letter of Hart, April 26, 1973; Item No. 90
    - Letter of Peter Hanff with article on Early Ban. Imprints, 29 November 1972; Item No. 90
    - My letter to Peter Hanff, October 16, 1972; Item No. 90
  - List of Copyright of H.H. Bancroft & Co. Publications, 1857-1870; Item No. 91; 4 pages (Box 4)
    Prepared for Henry R.Wagner by Miss Edith M. Coulter in 1948 with copy.
  - Bancroft Lib. Lacks H.H. Bancroft & Co. Pub., Item No. 91; 3 pages with copy (Box 4)
  - Census of H.H. Bancroft & Co. imprints, Item No. 91; 1 page, 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - Paper making, Item No. 92 (Box 4)
    - Note of extract from Titus Fey Cronise Paper making in California, Item No. 92 (Box 4)
    - Letter from the Huntington Library, Item No. 92 (Box 4)
    - Letter from HRW to Cone Free Librarian, October 18, 1950; Item No. 92 (Box 4)
    - Letter from Librarian Mason Librarian Great Barrington, October 31, 1950; Item No. 92 (Box 4)
    - Extract from Horace Lyman Weeks A History of Paper manufacturing in the UC, Item No. 92; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - Extract of HRW work, Item No. 92; 4 pages. (Box 4)
    - Bancroft imprint [?] Not Found, Item No. 93; 2 copies, 6 pages; 4 pages; 16 pages (Box 4)
  - The Templeton Crocker Collection of Western American in California Historical Library, 1936; Item No. 94; gray board, green spine (Box 4)
    - Edna Parratt to HRW California Teacher, December 14, 1949; Item No. 94; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Bancroft published in California Historical Society Library exclusive of the Works, Item No. 94; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - H.H. Bancroft & Co. Publ. Checked by C.H.S., Item No. 94; 6 pages (Box 4)
    - Bancroft Imprints and The Works all checked by CHS, Item No. 94; 2 pages. (Box 4)
    - Pub. adv. in Pacific Coast Series Fifth Reader A.L. Bancroft & Co., (copyright 1874); Item No. 94; 1 page. (Box 4)
    - The Bancroft Publications all checked by CHS, Item No. 94; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - The History Co. Publications all checked by CHS, Item No. 94; 3 pages (Box 4)
    - HRW to Edna Martin, June 14, 1951; Item No. 94; 1 page (Box 4)
      (re French ed. Native Races)
    - "My notes", Item No. 94; 2 holograph pages (Box 4)
    - Goodspeeds Western Scout, vol. 1, February 1, 1952; Item No. 94; 1 Broadside (both sides) (Box 4)
      - Letter of HRW to Edna Parrett pinned to it, February 8, 1952; Item No. 94; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter of Ruth Axe to Reference Librarian, November 4, 1972; Item No. 94; 1 page (Box 4)
      - Reply, November 15, 1972; Item No. 94; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter R. Axe to Reference Librarian, March 5, 1973; Item No. 94; 1 page (Box 4)
      - Reply Mrs. Swingle, March 15, 1973; Item No. 94; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Mr. Absjian to Ruth Axe, March 23, 1977; Item No. 94; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Not Bancroft, Item No. 94; 1 xerox (Box 4)
  - List of Pioneer Society Items, Item No. 95; 9 pages (Box 4)
  - Doxsee references, Item No. 96; 11 pages (newsprint) (Box 4)
  - California State Library, Item No. 97 (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Miss Edith Coulter, August 3, 1948; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Miss Edith Coulter, July 6, 1948; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Miss Coulter to HRW, July 9, 1948; Item No. 97; 1 page (holograph) (Box 4)
    - Miss Coulter to HRW, July 30 1948; Item No. 97; 1 page (holograph) (Box 4)
    - "Some of Bancroft & Co's Publications all checked", Item No. 97; 4 pages (Box 4)
    - Extract from The Bookseller, Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Miss Mabel Gillis, August 23, 1948; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter Miss Gillis to HRW, September 28, 1948; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Miss Gillis, August 9, 1948; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Miss Gillis, October 12, 1948; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter Miss Gillis, December 12, 1949; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Caroline Wenzel, February 1, 1950; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Caroline Wenzel, March 24, 1950; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to Caroline Wenzel, January 9, 1949; Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
    - California State Library List of their H.H.Bancroft & Co., holdings all checked, Item No. 97; 3 pages (Box 4)
    - A Report on the location of Early California Imprints for the California State Library in Greenwood's California Imprints (by Rllen R. Ottley), Item No. 97; 7 pages (Box 4)
    - The American Almanac 1856 not Ban, Item No. 97; tp xerox (Box 4)
    - Letter Ruth Axe to California State Library, September 9, 1972; Item No. 97; 3 pages (Box 4)
    - Bancroft publ. not yet located but checked by CSL for some they have, Item No. 97; 1 page (Box 4)
  - Los Angeles Public Library, Item No. 98 (Box 4)
    Bancroft imprints all checked with lib. nos.
  - Biographical, Item No. 99 (Box 4)
    - Bancroft children's reminiscences, Item No. 99; 7 pages (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Mr. Brigham AAS re Bancroft, August 30, 1948; Item No. 99; 1 page xerox (Box 4)
      - Reply, September 1, 1948; Item No. 99; 1 page xerox (Box 4)
    - Mr. Lohmann, Secretary Yale University, September 8, 1948; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter from Harry J. Crosby to HRW re Clarence King, January 12, 1951; Item No. 99; 1 page. (Box 4)
      - Reply HRW, January 16, 1951; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - R. Axe to Crosby, December 29, 1963; Item No. 99; 1 page (newsprint) (Box 4)
    - Notes on John Swett, Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW to W.W. Robinson re Watts, November 17, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
      - Reply W.W. Robinson re Watts, November 21, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Sara Bancroft Fry to HRW, March 20, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page holograph (Box 4)
    - Letter John Kemble to HRW re travel exp. of Bancroft, December 25, 1949; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Oassenger list, Item No. 99; 1 page negative photostat (Box 4)
    - Letter Caroline Wenzel Bancroft's travels, April 13, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Dates of arrivals and departures, Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW thank you and also for news of HHB diary in Ban, Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - From HRW to Griffin Bancroft, November 7, 1949; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Reply Philip Bancroft, February 13, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Philip Bancroft, February l7, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
      - Philip Bancroft reply, March 1, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page, holograph (Box 4)
    - HRW to Philip Bancroft, March 8, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Philip Bancroft, October 30, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Mrs. Chas P. Lineweaver, March 8, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
      - Reply C. Lineweaver, March 23, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page, holograph (Box 4)
    - HRW to L.B. Harrison, March 8, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Philip Bancroft to HRW reply to below, February 13, 1954; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Philip Bancroft, February 3, 1954; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Charles Forward, November 6, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
      re Mrs. Richards daughter of Kate. (I.R. Axe have since met her daughter Mrs. Swisher who was helpful with Oak acct.)
      - Reply, November 9, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW to Charles Forward, November 10, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter of Mabel Gillis, August 20, 1948; Item No. 99 (Box 4)
    - Biographical from State Lib. Albert Little Bancroft, Item No. 99; 3 pages (Box 4)
    - Biographical from State Lib. Samuel Leonidas Simpson, Item No. 99; 6 pages (Box 4)
    - Biographical from State Lib. Andrew W. Patterson, Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - William Henry Knight, Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Arthur H. Bell, Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Ed McGowan, Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Frederick Peter Stone, Item No. 99; 4 pages (Box 4)
    - Letter of HRW to Caroline Wenzel thanks for biographical material, Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter re ALB and Honey Lake, August 18, 1950; Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Article: Has Fraud been Practiced? ALB, Item No. 99; 1 page xerox (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW reply, Item No. 99; 1 page (Box 4)
    - San Diego Union, December 12, 1976; Item No. 99; 1 page xerox (Box 4)
    - San Diego Union, January 4, 1977; Item No. 99; 1 page xerox (Box 4)
    - San Diego Union, January 1, 1963; Item No. 99; 1 page xerox (Box 4)
  - Ed Carpenter and Huntington Library, Item No. 100 (Box 4)
    - Letter to HRW, February 1, 1949; Item No. 100; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter to HRW, July 25, 1949; Item No. 100; 1 page (Box 4)
    - List Entries in Huntington Library Catalog under HHB except Works checked, Item No. 100; 4 pages (Box 4)
    - List from Mrs. Hager checked, March 4, 1964; Item No. 100; 10 pages (newsprint) (Box 4)
  - Library of Congress, Item No. 101 (Box 4)
    [see maps]
    - Letter, November 18, 1949; Item No. 101; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter reply HRW, November 23, 1949; Item No. 101; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW, October 31, 1949; Item No. 101; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter LC form, October 26, 1949; Item No. 101; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter HRW, October 21, 1949; Item No. 101; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter, October 12, 1949; Item No. 101; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Copyright office L.C., November 30, 1940; Item No. 101; 1 page (Box 4)
    - HRW, September 14, 1949; Item No. 101; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Bancroft imprints, Item No. 101; 6 pages, L.C. xerox cards (Box 4)
  - Maps, including Library of Congress and Almanacs, Item No. 102 (Box 4)
    - Bancroft Library: 2 3x5 cards maps, Item No. 102; 1 long brown envelope (Box 4)
    - HHB and ALB Maps unlocated, Item No. 102; 3 pages, newsprint (Box 4)
    - My notes on Henry Hancock survey, Item No. 102; 1 yellow page (Box 4)
    - Bancroft's Maps in Library of Congress, Item No. 102; 3 pages (Box 4)
    - Extract 'Wheat's Mapping the A....', Item No. 102; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Maps and locations, etc., Item No. 102; 3 pages, xerox and notes (Box 4)
    - List of Printed Maps of California Supplement to ... Board of Regents, Berkeley 1887, Library Bulletin No. 9, Item No. 102; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - "My notes on newsprint of above", Item No. 102; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - Description of Bancroft map in Clark Library prepared by Ed Carpenter, (December 14, 1949); Item No. 102; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter from B. Whiting to R. Axe, December 21, 1957; Item No. 102; 1 page (Box 4)
    - 1 card from B. Whiting to R. Axe, January 22, 1958; Item No. 102 (Box 4)
    - 1 letter from Peggy Christian, June 22, 1971; Item No. 102 (Box 4)
    - 1 letter from Warren Howell, May 28, 1973; Item No. 102 (Box 4)
    - 1 letter to Wesley Catlin CSL, March 29, 1973; Item No. 102 (Box 4)
    - 1 letter reply, Item No. 102 (Box 4)
    - 3 maps Cal State Library, Item No. 102; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Almanacs, Item No. 102 (Box 4)
      - Letter of Clarence S. Brigham A.A.S., January 7, 1949; Item No. 102 (Box 4)
      - List of California Almanacs in AAS to 1870, Item No. 102 (Box 4)
      - Letter of HRW to CSL, April 4, 1949; Item No. 102 (Box 4)
      - Am. Almanac 1857 not Ban., Item No. 102; Xerox (Box 4)
  - Lithographs, Item No. 103 (Box 4)
    - Bird's Eye Views of California Cities by Mary Lou de Lapp, Item No. 103; 14 pages (Box 4)
    - Letter NYPL to HRW with list, March 16, 1954; Item No. 103; 2 pages (Box 4)
    - Letter to Bob Becker Peter Hanff Suzanne Gallup Bancroft Library, April 3, 1977; Item No. 103; 1 page (Box 4)
      - Reply, May 9, 1977; Item No. 103; 1 page (Box 4)
    - My notes on Lithos, Item No. 103; 2 yellow pages, 3 white pages (Box 4)
    - Letter of Bowers Museum, July 12, 1977; Item No. 103; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter of Bowers Museum, July 5, 1977; Item No. 103; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Letter to CHS, May 27, 1977; Item No. 103; 1 page (Box 4)
      - Reply, June 9, 1977; Item No. 103; 1 page (Box 4)
    - Notes, Item No. 103; 6 yellow pages (Box 4)
    - Notes from Peters California on Stone, Item No. 103; 1 page (Box 4)
  - The Works and the Native Races (cont.), Item No. 104 (Box 5)
    - HRW to S W Museum, July 15, 1949; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - HRW to S W Museum, August 5, 1949; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - F.W. Hodge ingloses, Item No. 104; 1 page holograph (Box 5)
    - Circular from Lummis papers re Bancroft, (dated 1907); Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - F.W. Lodge letter, October 4, re books, Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - HLRW to Stanford University Library re Bancroft History of California, Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
      - Reply, December 2, 1949; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - HRW to Edna Parratt CHS, January 18, 1950; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
      re Native Races and Book of Fair
      - Reply?, October 30 1950; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - Dawson re History of California, September 17, 1950; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - Harold Holmes, November 3, 1950; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - HRW to H.P. Kraus re Native Races, June 1, 1951; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - List of CHS Works, October 26, 1954; Item No. 104; 1 short page (Box 5)
    - Letter CHS, November 1, 1954; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - Anna Marie Hager to CHS, February 27, 1964; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - Accompanying list not checked, Item No. 104; 6 pages (Box 5)
    - Reply James Abajian, March 3, 1964; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - Circular Alta California bookstore Bancroftiana, Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - Bancroftiana, October 15, 1970; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - Edna Parratt CHS, March 28, 1951; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - Letter HRW to CHS, April 10, 1951; Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
    - List general CHS, Item No. 104; 2 pages (Box 5)
    - List Bancroftiana (gen'l.) don't know from whom, Item No. 104; 4 pages xerox (Box 5)
    - Misrepresentations in the Bancroft Works by John Howell, Item No. 104; 1 page (Box 5)
- Xerox copies, 13 items
  - Schoolbooks, Item No. 105 (Box 5)
    - HRW letter to Library Education Department UC, February 21, 1949; Item No. 105; 1 page (Box 5)
    - RG Cowan letter re his father's schoolbook collection, Item No. 105; 1 page (Box 5)
    - HRW to James Babb, Yale University Library, May 23, 1949; Item No. 105; 1 page (Box 5)